SHRATHINTH VENKATESH

 $(262) \cdot 421 \cdot 5281 \diamond \text{venkate3@uwm.edu}$ 1714, E. Beverly Rd, #7 ♦ Shorewood, WI 53211 shrathinth.com

SUMMARY

Economist/Applied micro-econometrician with a track record of consistently and creatively solving a diverse set of problems. Experienced with analysing survey data and medical claims data from public and private insurance providers. Implemented a wide variety of empirical strategies to examine changes in labour market outcomes, health outcomes and their effects. Drawn robust conclusions from limited data and indirect treatment observation.

EDUCATION

University of Wisconsin - Milwaukee

(Expected) 2021

PhD in Economics

Focus: Labor Economics, Economics of Education, Health Economics

PES Institute of Technology, India

2013

BE in Mechanical Engineering

Focus: Material Science

EXPERIENCE

Graduate Research Assistant

August 2017 - December 2019

College of Nursing, Department of Economics

University of Wisconsin - Milwaukee

- · Assessed the impact of the PERISCOPE perinatal health intervention using claims data from Medicaid and private insurance providers in Wisconsin.
- · Used propensity score matching and difference-in-differences regressions to find a 20% increase in prescription use and a \$310 reduction in emergency costs.
- · Used machine learning techniques including random forest, decision tree and K-nearest neighbours in R for variable selection and testing.
- · Reported the results of our study in non-technical language.
- · Communicated and worked with health professionals to create appropriate empirical models.

Lecturer

September 2020 - May 2021

Department of Economics

University of Wisconsin - Whitewater

- · Teaching applied business statistics and principles of microeconomics.
- · Creating content and teaching students in a Hy-Flex format.

Graduate Teaching Assistant

August 2014 - May 2020

University of Wisconsin - Milwaukee Department of Economics

- · Taught a diverse set of students with a wide range of technical backgrounds.
- · Clearly communicated technical statistics and econometrics.
- · Taught data analysis using R and STATA to undergraduate and graduate students with little prior knowledge.
- · Had full control of 4 different courses across 8 semesters.

TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

Skills		Applied econometrics, Machine learning, Data Analysis
Tools	Proficient	STATA, R, Matlab, LATEX
	Familiar	Python, SQL, SAS, SPSS, E-Views, JAVA, C++

RESEARCH

"The Emerging College Hours Premium for Men" (revision asked for by Edu	ication Economics)
"The Returns to Drinking: Social Workers or Social Jobs?" with SJ Adams, JS Hey	wood & D Ullman
Under Review	
"Are the Returns to Education Still Rising?"	Working Paper
"Changes in the Returns to Education: Evidence from Three Cohorts of the NLSY"	Working Paper
"Estimating the Effects of the Periscope Project" with SJ Adams & JJ Doering	In Progress
"Changes in education's effect on job sorting"	In Progress

PRESENTATIONS AND HONORS

Midwest Economic Association Annual Meeting, St.Louis, MO	2019
Wisconsin Economics Association Annual Meeting, Stevens Point, WI	2019
University of Wisconsin - Milwaukee Economics Labor Lunch	2019
University of Wisconsin - Milwaukee Applied Microeconomics group	2019
Richard Perlman Prize for Outstanding Paper in Labor Economics	2018
University of Wisconsin - Milwaukee Chancellors Graduate student award	2014 & 2015

PROFESSIONAL SERVICE

Midwest Economic Association Annual Meeting, St. Louis, MO	Discussant	2019
Graduate Student Applied Microeconomics Group, UWM	${\it Co-organizer}$	2019

PROFESSIONAL ASSOCIATIONS

American Economic Association Midwest Economic Association

REFERENCES

Provided upon request.